

# Web Developer



#### **PROFILE**

Web developer with a background in management and intellectual property law. Highly organised and valued team member with great interpersonal skills. I am experienced at working under pressure to meet deadlines.

I love finding solutions to problems, and show incredible persistence and perseverance in doing so..apparently having young children has truly levelled-up my patience. Who'd have thought?

#### **PHONE**

0049-178-682851

#### **EMAIL**

ianflemingdeveloper@gmail.com

#### **PORTFOLIO**

www.ianflemingdeveloper.com

#### **LINKEDIN**

www.linkedin.com/in/i-fleming/

#### **GITHUB**

https://github.com/ianfleming464/

### **EXPERTISE**

- JavaScript (ES6)
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
- React, React Native
- Node.js
- API configuration
- AWS, Heroku
- MongoDB, SQL, Firebase
- Git version control
- TDD (Jest, Cucumber)
- Postman

#### **LANGUAGES**

- English (native)
- German (B1)

### **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

### My 1980s Movie API

- -Built a full-stack movie application which allows users to browse movies, create a profile, log in/out securely create a favourites list, and show director/genre info.
- -Created using the MERN stack, JWT authentication, MVC design pattern, and deployed via Heroku.

### **Meetup App**

- -Built a serverless, progressive web application which takes info from the Meetup API (and OAuth 2), and displays events in a city of your choice. Created during the Meetup Pro API 30-day trial period, so currently functioning in offline mode.
- -Made with React, AWS Lambda, tested extensively with Jest/Enzyme.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# May 2017 - now

**Grünecker Patent- und Rechtsanwälte, Munich |** Formalprozessabteilung Sachbearbeiter / Legal Assistant

- -Controlling and coordinating all formal processes relating to industrial designs/trademarks. Reporting on registration, enacting payments, dealing with multiple deadlines, navigating a huge workload.
- -Enhanced efficiency by fully-digitising the fee payment/deferment schedule. This made it legible and understandable, aiding in better prioritisation of work and resulting in 100% of all deadlines met.

#### March 2015 - March 2017

# The Keg Bar, Munich | Bar manager

-Hired, trained and motivated staff to cultivate a sense of team and a customer-focused approach, delegated work, accurately planned drink/food orders depending on demand/upcoming events.

### August 2008 - June 2014

The Book Centre, Waterford, Ireland | Book department worker, duty/weekend manager

-Analysed inventory and planned accordingly, ordering books for ca. 8 different sections to ensure we always had exactly what the customer wanted before they even knew they wanted it.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Career Foundry GmbH**

### Full-Stack Development Certificate, January 2020 - November 2020

- -Attained a fluency in Javascript, and subsequently React, React Native and Node.js.
- -Built a personal portfolio site from scratch to showcase my work, including: a fully-functional React Native chat app for Android and IOS, several apps employing external APIs (including a Meetup app and a Pokedex clone) and notably an entire full-stack movie app created using the MERN stack and REST.

# University College Limerick, Ireland

MA in Music Technology, 2012-2013

- -Graduated with a 1.1
- -Wrote a peer-reviewed scientific paper on a piece of music I composed and released, based on the voice of author Harlan Ellison (<u>'I Have No Mouth (pts. 1-6) Introducing Postdigital Spectralism'</u>
- Leonardo Music Journal LMJ24 Dec 2014)

### University College Cork, Ireland

BA in English and Sociology, 2000-2003